Desmond O'Grady papers, 1953-2001
Emory University
- Writings by Desmond O'Grady, 1956-2002, Series 2; Boxes 28 - 51
  - Prose, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 39 - 40
    - "Spoleto Festival of Two Worlds," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - "Spoleto, Separezioni," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - "Springtime Sailing Yugoslavia," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - "The State of Poetry in Ireland," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - "20th Century Poetry in Ireland," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 29)
    - "The Wanderer," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - "A Wandering Celt in Yugoslavia," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - "'The Windhover': Gerard Manly Hopkins," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - "With Kitchenor to Khartoum," TS (Box 40, Folder 33)
    - "Yugoslavia for Autumn," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - Short Stories and Novels
    - "The Inheritance," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - "Introduction," MS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 36)
    - "The Woman at the Well," TS (Box 40, Folder 37)
    - Drama
    - "Stephen Failure," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified Prose
    - Unidentified prose, MS and TS (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - Translations by O'Grady, 1968-1997, Subseries 2.3; Boxes 41-49: folder 6
    - Off Licence (1968)
    - "Adolescent," TS (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Adrift," TS (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Cruel Farewell," TS (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "Flight," TS (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "Friendship," TS (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "I Am Raftery the Poet," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "Kathleen, the Daughter of Houlahan," TS w/ corrections [variant title: "To Silvia"] (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "Ligurian Evening," TS (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Nostalgia," TS (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "The Past," TS (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "Poem," TS (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "The Poet Loves from Afar," MS (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "Seagulls," TS (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "This Morning in the Dawn," TS (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "To Death," TS (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "A Welcome to Summer," TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - The Gododin (1971)
    - "The Gorchanau: Three Laments," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Book jacket material, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - A Night with Hamlet and Other Observations Vladimir Holan, (ca. 1980)
    - " A Night with Hamlet and Other Observations," TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Book jacket material, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Grecian Glances: Versions from the Classical Anthology (1981)
    - Grecian Glances: Versions from the Classical Anthology, TS (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Seven Arab Odes (1990)
    - "The Black Knight," MS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - "The King Killer," MS w/ corrections [variant title: "The Regicide"] (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - "The Leper," MS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - "The Man with the Crooked Staff," MS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - "The Moralist," MS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - "The One the Gods Loved," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - "The Vagabond Prince," MS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Seven Arab Odes, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Seven Arab Odes, TS (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Seven Arab Odes, TS (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Seven Arab Odes, TS (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Seven Arab Odes, TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Book jacket material, MS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Preliminary table of contents, MS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Preliminary title page, MS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Ten Modern Arab Poets (1992)
    - Bashir, Al-Tijani Yusuf, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - al-Jabal, Badawi, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Madi, Ilya Abu, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Matar, Muhammad 'Afifi, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Naji, Ibrahim, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Nuwas, Abu, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - al-Sabur, Salah' Abd, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - al-Sayyab, Badr Shakir, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Shauqi, Ahmad, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Tuqan, Ibrahim, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Book jacket material, MS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Preliminary table of contents, MS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Alternative Manners (1993)
    - "Candles," TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Ithaka," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - "One Night," MS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - "Windows," MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Alternative Manners, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Alternative Manners, proofs w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Book jacket material, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Preliminary table of contents, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Trawling Tradition (1994)
    - Classical Arabic Introduction, MS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Classical Chinese Poetry, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Early Christian Poetry, TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Fenian Poetry, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Irish Country Poetry, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Irish Courtly Love Poetry, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Medieval Welsh Poetry, TS w/ corrections (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Akhmatova, Anna, MS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Alberti, Rafael, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Alcaeus, TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Archilochus, TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Bachmann, Ingeborg, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Bertolucci, Attilio, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Bettocchi, Carlo, MS and TS w/ correcctions (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Bigongiari, Piero, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Caedmon's Canto, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Campana, Dino, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Cardarelli, Vencenzo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Cavafy, C.P., MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - d'Andrea, Ercole Ugo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - De Santis, Ennio, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Garufi, Guido, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Gentilli, Alessandro, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Govoni, Corrado, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Guidacci, Margherita, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Guiliani, Alfredo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Hierro, Jose, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Hikmet, Nazim, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Holan, Vladimir, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Ivask, Astrid, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Ivask, Ivar, MS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Kirsh, Sarah, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Kouchag, Nahabed, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Lippi, Massimo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Lorca, Frederico Garcia, MS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Luzi, Mario, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Mettais-Cartier, Gerard, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Montale, Eugenio, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Onofri, Arturo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Pagliarani, Elio, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Palazzeschi, Aldo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Pasolini, Pier Paolo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Pavese, Cesare, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Pozzi, Antonia, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Quasimodo, Salvatore, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Rebora, Clemente, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Rosselli, Amelia, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Rummo, Paul-Eerik, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Saba, Umberto, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Sanguineti, Eduardo, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Sappho, TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Scottus, Sedulius, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Seferis, George, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Sereni, Vittorio, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Simonides, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Spanizani, Maria Luise, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Tomicic, Zlatko, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Tuqan, Fadwa, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Ungaretti, Giuseppe, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Valente, Jose Angel, MS w/ corrections (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Venslova, Tomas, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Zuo Si, TS w/ corrections (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Book jacket material, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Preface, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Preliminary table of contents, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Title page, MS w/ corrections (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Proof w/ corrections [1 of 4] (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Proof w/ corrections [2 of 4] (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Proof w/ corrections [3 of 4] (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Proof w/ corrections [4 of 4] (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Golden Odes of Love (1997)
    - Proof w/ corrections (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished Collections of Translations
    - Italian Notebook, MS and TS w/ corrections (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Rehearsals, TS w/ corrections [translations of Constantine Cavafy] (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Translations
    - Unidentified translations, MS and TS (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified translations, MS and TS (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Translations of O'Grady, Subseries 2.4; Box 49: folders 7-9
    - "Fo Fo" [translation of "Fo Fo," by Cecilia Miniucchi], TS (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - "Il fiume Shannon" [translation of "Shannon River," by Cecilia Miniucchi], TS (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Il Galata Morente [translation of The Dying Gaul], Proofs w/ corrections (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Notebooks, Subseries 2.5; Boxes 50 - 51
    - Notebook with poetry [includes poetry from Tipperary] (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with poetry [includes poetry from Tipperary] (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with poetry (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with poetry, prose, and translation (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with poetry, prose, and translation (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Notebook with poetry and notes on Cavafy (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Notebook with translations [includes translations of Constantine Cavafy] (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Notebook with translations [includes translation of The Gododdin] (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Notebook with translations (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Notebooks with notes on T.S. Eliot's The Wasteland [2] (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Notebook with notes on James Joyce (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Notebook with notes on Celtic history (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Notebook with notes on Persian poetry (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Notebook with notes on translation (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Notebook with lecture notes (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Notebook with lecture notes (Box 51, Folder 6)
- Writings by others, Series 3; Boxes 52 -54
  The series consists of both critical and creative works by other writers. The works are arranged alphabetically by author. Works by unidentified authors are arranged alphabetically by title at the end of each subseries. Many of the works are dedicated to O'Grady.
  Organized into two subseries: (3.1) Poems by others, (3.2) Prose by others, and (3.3) Translations by others.
  - Poetry by others, Subseries 3.1; Boxes 52 - 53: folder 49
    - Beardsley, Ellen, "From Amsterdam," TS (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Beardsley, Ellen, untitled, MS (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Byrne, Elena, Sanctuary of Hunger, TS (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Castleman, David, "Without Dreams Our World is Mindless Death," TS (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Chisman, Forrest, "Achilles," TS (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - d'Ailly, Gisele, MS (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - DeSuze, Diane, untitled, MS (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Domenicano, Massimo, untitled, TS (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Duranti, Ricardo, "Burying Wiley," TS (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Emanuel, Ben-Zion, Honey Out of the Carcass, TS (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Ferrara, Ranieri Walter, untitled, TS (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Freeze, Rick, TS (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Galioto, Salvatore, TS (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Gayton, Thomas L., "Bonfires of Belfast," TS (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Gayton, Thomas L., "Desmond O'Grady The Dying Gaul," TS (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Hart, Jonathan, Breath and Dust, TS (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Hashmi, Alamgir, "Winter Flight," TS (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - James, Laurence, "Jack," TS (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - James, Laurence, Ricegrain & Razorblades, TS (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - MacIntyre, Tom, "Father," TS (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Meilen, Bill, Akbar, TS (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Meilen, Bill, Fields of Pain, TS (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Meilen, Bill, Trumpet Shadows, TS (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Metascas, Petros, "Naoussa," MS (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Mulholland, Peggy, "Happy as a Clam," TS (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Murphy, Hayden, "Clouds Wear Feathered Gloves," TS (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Murray, Paul, Office of the Dead, TS (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - O'Brien, Anthony, "Autume," MS (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - O'Brien, Anthony, "Birdsong," TS (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - O'Brien, Anthony, "Gypsies," TS (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - O'Brien, Anthony, "Reasons," TS (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - O'Brien, Anthony, "Waiting," TS (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Owen, Stephen, "Early Poems," MS (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - Owen, Stephen, "Hym to Sirius," TS (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - Owen, Stephen, The Wounded Centaur, TS (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - Quinn, Brian, "Last Voyage," TS (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - Quinn, Brian, "Muddy Carthy's Mother," TS (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - Quinn, Brian, "Once More Facing Out," MS (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - Quinn, Brian, "Your Eyes Semaphore," TS (Box 52, Folder 39)
    - Quinn, Brian, "Youth," MS (Box 52, Folder 40)
    - Quinn, Brian, untitled, MS (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - Redding, J.C, MS (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Richards, David, "Des O'Watha (And His Brother)," TS (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Richards, David, "Deteriorata," TS (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Richards, David, untitled, TS (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Ruffilli, Paolo, By Hook or By Crook, TS (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Salabe, Giovanna, Poesia, TS (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Sandy, Stephen, "Condensation," TS (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Simmons, James, "The Lascar and the Lady," TS (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Stubbs, John Heath, "Photographer," TS (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Wilde-Menozzi, Wallis, "Rain," TS (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Zito, Eleanor Shiel, "World War II Blackout," MS (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified author
    - "And After, Silence," MS (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - "The Big Apple Has a Worm In It," TS (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - "Comparisons," TS (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - "Cork," TS (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - "Drams & Chasers, Shetland," TS (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - "El Salvador," TS (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - "Erosion," TS (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - "From Here to There and Back Again," TS (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - "I Know What's Real," MS (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - "The Island," TS (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - "Legs," MS (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - "Limerick," TS (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - "The Limerick Rake," MS (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - "Longing," MS (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - "Lullabye II," MS (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - "Maybe I'm Dreaming," MS (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - "Message to Mother," MS (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - "Music from the Soul," MS (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - "My Brother Joe...," TS (Box 53, Folder 30)
    - "N.B.," MS (Box 53, Folder 31)
    - "O'Grady at Sea on His Birthday," MS (Box 53, Folder 32)
    - "Old Man of India," MS (Box 53, Folder 33)
    - "On Your 50th Birthday," MS (Box 53, Folder 34)
    - "Overture," MS (Box 53, Folder 35)
    - "People Like Us," MS (Box 53, Folder 36)
    - "Ronnie the Ref," MS (Box 53, Folder 37)
    - "The Sacred Wood," MS (Box 53, Folder 38)
    - "Set it in Stone," TS (Box 53, Folder 39)
    - "Spacewalk," TS (Box 53, Folder 40)
    - "The Spinster's Dream," TS (Box 53, Folder 41)
    - "Sulpica's Advice to a Lover on His Birthday," TS (Box 53, Folder 42)
    - "Thales," MS (Box 53, Folder 43)
    - "Three Bulls," MS (Box 53, Folder 44)
    - "The Tribe," MS (Box 53, Folder 45)
    - "Vista dal Campidoglio," MS (Box 53, Folder 46)
    - "Visiting Hours," TS (Box 53, Folder 47)
    - Unidentified collection of poems, TS (Box 53, Folder 48)
    - Unidentifed poetry, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 49)
  - Prose by others, Subseries 3.2; Boxes 53: folder 50 - 54: folder 18
    - Benson, Donald, "A Compelling Love for Life," TS (Box 53, Folder 50)
    - Brady, Liam, "The Relic," TS (Box 53, Folder 51)
    - Castleman, David, "On Isolation," TS [See Subseries 3.1, Castleman, David, "Without Dreams our World is Mindless Death," TS] (Box -, -)
    - Chiodo, Nail, "The Insignificant Other," TS (Box 53, Folder 52)
    - DeSuze, Diane Burney, "Story #1," TS (Box 53, Folder 53)
    - Emanuel, Herzl, Diana and the Sculptor, TS (Box 53, Folder 54)
    - Fennell, Desmond, "The Fragility of Postwestern Civilisation," TS (Box 53, Folder 55)
    - Galioto, Salvatore, "A Visit with Roma and the Romans-Part II," TS (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Hutchins, Patricia, "The Leesons," TS (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Ivask, Astrid, "Coming Home," TS (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - James, Laurence, "From Ithaka to Tipperary," TS (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Jenkins, Alan, untitled, TS (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - MacKay, Hugh Stanley, The Image of Kingship: Sovereignty in the Tales of the Tuatha De Danann, TS (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - McCarty, Thos. Vere, Behind the Icon, TS (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - McDermott, Eamon, "Cremations," TS (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - McIntyre, Tom, The Great Hunger, TS [stage adaptation of Patrick Kavanagh's The Great Hunger] (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - O'Kennedy, Percy, "Dropping a Clanger," TS (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Russell, Peter, "Pian Di Sco," TS (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Salabe, Giovanna, Prosa, TS [See Subseries 3.1, Poetry by Others, Salabe, Giovanna, Poesia] (Box -, -)
    - Salim, Ali, The Oedipus Comedy, TS (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Shaheen, Mai, "A Mother's Tears," TS (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Shoukri, Doris Enright-Clark, "A Reading of Beckett's Unamable: 'the man on duty,'" TS (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Vesce, Thomas, The Human Alphabet, TS (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified author
    - "Hounds, Heroes, and Hospitallers in Early Irish Myth and Story," TS (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - "The Precious Present," TS (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - "Tarafa 6th C.," TS (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Translations by others, Subseries 3.3; Box 54: folders 19-21
    - Holzapfel, David, Uno Scandaglio: A Sounding, TS [translation of Italian Poetry] (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - O'Brien, Anthony, "Correspondences," MS [translation of Charles Baudelaire, "Correspondences"] (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - Stoenescu, Stefan, TS [translations of Rumanian poetry] (Box 54, Folder 21)
- Personal files, circa 1964-2001, Series 4; Boxes 55 - 63, OP 1
  The series consists of personal files of Desmond O'Grady including diaries and subject files. Of particular interest in Subseries 4.1 are the diaries 1964-2001 in which O'Grady recorded his thoughts and feelings on the major events in his life.
  The subject files (Subseries 4.2) contain printed material and correspondence relating to specific individuals such as Katherine Washburn and Noel Harrington and organizations such as Aosdana. Some subject files such as the Katherine Washburn, Noel Harrington, and Teaching Material files were created by O'Grady. Other files, such as Aosdana, financial papers, and drawings, were artificially assembled out of similar materials found throughout the papers.
  Organized into two subseries: (4.1) Personal and family items and (4.2) Subject files.
  - Personal and family items, 1964-2001, Subseries 4.1; Boxes 55 - 58
    - Address books, undated [3] (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Address book, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Address book, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1964-1971 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Diaries, 1987 [2] (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Diary, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Diaries, 1991 [2] (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Diary, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Diaries, 1994 [2] (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Diaries, 1996 [2] (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Diaries, 1997 [2] (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Diaries, 1999 [2] (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Diary, 2001 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Curriculum Vitae (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Financial papers [folder 1 of 2] (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Financial papers [folder 2 of 2] (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Genealogy, O’Grady family (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Last Will and Testament of Desmond James Bernard O'Grady [RESTRICTED] (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous personal and family items (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Subject files, Subseries 4.2; Boxes 59 - 63
    - Aosdana [folder 1 of 10] (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Aosdana [folder 2 of 10] (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Aosdana [folder 3 of 10] (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Aosdana [folder 4 of 10] (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Aosdana [folder 5 of 10] (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Aosdana [folder 6 of 10] (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Aosdana [folder 7 of 10] (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Aosdana [folder 8 of 10] (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Aosdana [folder 9 of 10] (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Aosdana [folder 10 of 10] (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Appearances and conferences (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Auden-Kallman collection finding aid (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Contracts (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Drawings (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Drawing of O'Grady (Box OP1)
    - Gordon, William J. Curriculum Vitae (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Harrington, Noel (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Post cards (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Publication records (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Reykjavik Literary Festival, 1995 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook of Italy (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Teaching material [folder 1 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Teaching material [folder 2 of 3] (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Teaching material [folder 3 of 3] (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Travel documents [folder 1 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Travel documents [folder 2 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Washburn, Katherine (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Printed material, 1953-2001, Series 5; Boxes 64 - 77, OP 2-12